<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data on Grow your Future with us</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/tags/data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data on Grow your Future with us</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/tags/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Value of Data Literacy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/2022/05/25/2022-05-25-the-value-of-data-literacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/2022/05/25/2022-05-25-the-value-of-data-literacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&#34;Data to Knowledge to Action&#34; src=&#34;data_gov.png&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin: auto;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-reasons-why-understanding-data-is-key&#34;&gt;4 Reasons why understanding data is key&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s digital age, data is everywhere. Being able to understand and analyze data is known as data literacy. In both educational and professional settings, data literacy skills are vital to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.precisely.com/blog/data-integrity/data-literacy-what-it-is-and-why-it-matters&#34;&gt;success&lt;/a&gt;. Data is virtually in every space. We are constantly looking at numbers, text, images, videos, and our personal data is always being collected as we are actively using our phones or computers. Whether we realize it or not, data is always at our fingertips. Increasing our knowledge and personal skill set to collect, store, clean and analyze data allows us to understand how to apply critical thinking skills to everyday problems. Here are four reasons why understanding data is of great value to college students, and people entering the workforce.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Thrilling, Statistic-Filled Weekend at Chico State Data Fest 2022</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/2022/05/04/2022-05-04-datafest-2022-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/2022/05/04/2022-05-04-datafest-2022-recap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;chico-state-data-fest-2022-recap&#34;&gt;Chico State Data Fest 2022 Recap&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On April 1-3rd, Chico State University hosted the ASA DataFest 2022. DataFest is an event hosted by the Chico State Data Initiative (DSI), organized by the Mathematics &amp;amp; Statistics department and Project DA-FANH&amp;rsquo;s project director Robin Donatello. Students were presented with undisclosed data on Friday and then worked through the weekend to gain the best insights into the confidential, real-world data sets. After long nights and early mornings, teams presented their findings to the experienced panel of judges for a chance at prizes and certificates. The event is part of the university’s efforts to provide training, expand collaboration and encourage new research in the field of Data Science and Data Analytics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
