<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Grow your Future with us</title>
    <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Grow your Future with us</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:6407/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Free Python Workshop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2024/08/10/2024-08-30-software-carpentry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2024/08/10/2024-08-30-software-carpentry/</guid>
      <description>We’re excited to be hosting a Software Carpentry workshop and hope you are too. Our upcoming workshop will be on August 19th - 21st, 2024, from 9am - 1pm. A few notes:&#xA;Software Carpentry aims to help researchers get their work done in less time and with less pain by teaching them basic research computing skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DA-FANH Internship Opportunity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2024/04/17/2024-04-17-internship-opportunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2024/04/17/2024-04-17-internship-opportunity/</guid>
      <description>Pre-Professional Experiential Learning Applications for the Fall 2024 intern cohort are now open!&#xA;This internship provides an authentic virtual (and in person when available) career experience, emphasizing problem solving, decision-making and remote collaboration skills, along with an understanding of leadership roles in a professional space.&#xA;We desire to recruit interns who represent our campus diversity in race, ethnicity, experience, age, gender, background, academic and personal interests.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>April Data Career Conversations - Women in Data Science</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2024/03/10/2024-04-11-ama-apr-chisoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2024/03/10/2024-04-11-ama-apr-chisoo/</guid>
      <description>Join us April 11, 11:00-11:50pm PST for Project DA-FANH&amp;rsquo;s monthly “Ask me Anything” speaker series. This time with Chisoo Lyons.&#xA;Chisoo is a Chief Program Director at Women in Data Science (WiDS), overseeing the portfolio of programs designed to elevate and empower women in the data science and AI fields.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>March Data Career Conversations - Data Science in the Agriculture sector</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2024/02/29/2024-03-0x-ama-mar-danny/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2024/02/29/2024-03-0x-ama-mar-danny/</guid>
      <description>Join us March 26th, 1:00 - 1:50 pm for Project DA-FANH&amp;rsquo;s monthly &amp;ldquo;Ask me Anything&amp;rdquo; speaker series. This time with Agricultural Biologist, Danny Maciel.&#xA;Danny is an Agricultural Biologist for the Butte County Agricultural Department. He was born in Southern California but raised in Baja California Mexico. Coming from a 3rd generation farming family, he&amp;rsquo;s made farming a huge part of his life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Driven Career Panel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2024/02/28/2024-03-13-career-panel24/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2024/02/28/2024-03-13-career-panel24/</guid>
      <description>Spring 2024 Career Panel Interested in careers in data? Well then do not miss this year&amp;rsquo;s Data Driven Career Panel happening on March 13th!&#xA;In collaboration with the San Bernardino and Chico State Career Centers, Project DA-FANH is virtually bringing four amazing professionals in the data science field to talk with students about their careers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>March Data Career Conversations - Data Science in Climate-Ecosystem Interaction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2024/02/25/2024-03-05-ama-mar-elmera/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2024/02/25/2024-03-05-ama-mar-elmera/</guid>
      <description>Join us on March 5th at 1:00-1:50pm PST, for Project DA-FANH&amp;rsquo;s monthly “Ask me Anything” speaker series. This time with Elmera Azadpour.&#xA;Elmera is a Data Scientist/Data Visualization Specialist with United States Geological Survey (USGS) in the Water Mission Area (WMA). Her work involves contributing to individual projects by applying reproducible workflows and data visualization techniques to capture and communicate complex data-intensive concepts to non-technical audiences.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>December Career Conversations - Student Intern Experinces</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2023/12/03/2023-12-07-ama-dec/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2023/12/03/2023-12-07-ama-dec/</guid>
      <description>Are you interested in careers that use data to make informed decisions in the Food, Agriculture, Natural Resources or Human sciences? Do you want to know how professionals landed their career or what they wished they did during college?&#xA;Then come check out this month&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Ask me Anything&amp;rdquo; speaker, Jesus Velazquez, a former Data Science Intern at JP Morgan.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>November Career Conversations - Health Equity Programs and Research</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2023/10/23/2023-11-07-ama-nov/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2023/10/23/2023-11-07-ama-nov/</guid>
      <description>Are you interested in careers that use data to make informed decisions in the Food, Agriculture, Natural Resources or Human sciences? Do you want to know how professionals landed their career or what they wished they did during college?&#xA;Then come check out this month&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Ask me Anything&amp;rdquo; speaker, Brian Castro, a Health Program and Research Associate at The National Alliance for Hispanic Health (the Alliance).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>October Career Conversations - Nutrition Security and Health Equity at the USDA</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2023/10/03/2023-10-ama-oct/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2023/10/03/2023-10-ama-oct/</guid>
      <description>Join us to officially kick off this semester&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Ask Me Anything&amp;rdquo; speaker with the amazing Dr. Sara Bleich. She is the Director of Nutrition Security and Health Equity in the Food and Nutrition Service at the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA).&#xA;This is not the only data driven career experience Dr.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project DA-FANH Fellow and Fall 2022 Intern Shares Her Experiences</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2023/07/07/2023-07-06-rosie-fellow-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2023/07/07/2023-07-06-rosie-fellow-reflection/</guid>
      <description>Are you interested in learning more about the DA-FANH internship or our fellowship? Keep reading to hear from our fellowship recipient and Fall 2022 intern, Rosie Diaz!&#xA;About Rosie Rosie is a current Chico State student majoring in Agricultural Business. She started at Chico State in the Fall of 2023 after transferring from a community college in her hometown.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post-Spring 2023 Career Panel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2023/04/24/2023-04-24-post-career-panel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2023/04/24/2023-04-24-post-career-panel/</guid>
      <description>Spring 2023 Career Panel The Spring 2023 Career Panel happened late in March and we had a great time meeting with four data science professionals and learning all about their careers. Our students had a lot of great questions to ask, and the career professionals were able to provide some amazing answers and helped to educate the students on what a career in data looks like.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learn About Recommended Courses From Our AMA Speakers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2023/04/12/2023-04-12-ama-highlight-courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2023/04/12/2023-04-12-ama-highlight-courses/</guid>
      <description>See a recap of highlights from our monthly Ask Me Anything sessions where our data science professionals share classes they recommended undergraduates take in order to succeed in graduate school or in their data science careers.&#xA;Our next AMA speaker for the month of April will be announced soon! Learn more and check out upcoming speakers here</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spring 2022 DA-FANH Intern Shares His Experiences</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2023/04/07/2023-04-07-intern-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2023/04/07/2023-04-07-intern-reflection/</guid>
      <description>Are you interested in the DA-FANH internship? Hear from one of our data science interns and read about his experiences!&#xA;About Sufyian Sufyian is a Chico State graduate who majored in anthropology with a minor in applied statistics. He currently works as a Research Assistant I for the Center For Data Insights.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Driven Career Panel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2023/03/23/2023-03-27-career-panel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2023/03/23/2023-03-27-career-panel/</guid>
      <description>Interested in careers in data? Well then do not miss the Chico State Data Driven Career Panel happening this month!&#xA;In collaboration with the Chico State Career Center, Project DA-FANH is virtually bringing four amazing professionals in the data science field to talk with students about their careers.&#xA;Come learn from industry experts about various careers in the Agriculture and Natural Sciences fields.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>March Career Conversations - Nutrition Security and Health Equity at the USDA</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2023/02/22/2023-03-07-ama-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2023/02/22/2023-03-07-ama-march/</guid>
      <description>This month&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Ask me Anything&amp;rdquo; speaker is the amazing Dr. Sara Bleich, the Director of Nutrition Security and Health Equity in the Food and Nutrition Service at the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA).&#xA;This is not the only data driven career experience Dr. Bleich has! Come and ask her questions about her experience as the Senior Advisor for COVID-19 in the Office of the Secretary at USDA, or as a Senior Policy Adviser for Food, Nutrition and Consumer Services and with the First Lady Michelle Obama’s Let’s Move!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>February Career Conversations - Data to Advance Pediatric Care</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2023/01/29/2023-02-10-ama-feb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2023/01/29/2023-02-10-ama-feb/</guid>
      <description>Happy Spring! We kick off February&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Ask me Anything&amp;rdquo; speaker series with Ricardo Aguilar, a Chico State Statistics Alumni now working to better the health of children. Come ask Ricardo about his journey to become a Research Computational Scientist I at Children&amp;rsquo;s Health of Orange County and learn how he supports research through project ideation, study design, data management, inferential statistics, statistical and machine learning model building, and manuscript writing to advance pediatric care.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Scholarship and Internship Opportunities</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2022/11/21/2022-11-23-scholarship-and-internship-opportunites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2022/11/21/2022-11-23-scholarship-and-internship-opportunites/</guid>
      <description>Upcoming Scholarship and Internship Opportunities As a student attending a Hispanic Serving Institution, there are many internships and scholarships that you may be eligible for! Keep reading to see some of the amazing opportunities that are waiting for you.&#xA;Interested in completing a paid internship in your field? The HACU National Internship Program offers students from all majors and all backgrounds paid internships in their field at a federal agency.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>November Career Conversations - Health Research &#43; Policy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2022/11/17/2022-11-17-ama-nov/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2022/11/17/2022-11-17-ama-nov/</guid>
      <description>Are you interested in careers that use data to make informed decisions in the Food, Agriculture, Natural Resources or Human sciences? Do you want to know how professionals landed their career or what they wished they did during college? Our monthly &amp;ldquo;Ask me Anything&amp;rdquo; speaker series continues with Natalia Cañas. Come ask Natalia about her journey to become a Research and Policy Associate at the National Alliance for Hispanic Health and learn how she uses research and data to understand the impact of COVID-19 on the Hispanic community.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>November Career Conversations - Survey Methods in Agriculture and Human Services</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2022/11/03/2022-11-03-ama-nov/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2022/11/03/2022-11-03-ama-nov/</guid>
      <description>Are you interested in careers that use data to make informed decisions in the Food, Agriculture, Natural Resources or Human sciences? Do you want to know how professionals landed their career or what they wished they did during college? Our monthly &amp;ldquo;Ask me Anything&amp;rdquo; speaker series continues with Jeff Gonzalez. Come ask Dr.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>October Career Conversations - Social Sciences &#43; Agricultural issues = impactful research!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2022/10/10/2022-10-10-ama-oct/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2022/10/10/2022-10-10-ama-oct/</guid>
      <description>Are you interested in careers that use data to make informed decisions in the Food, Agriculture, Natural Resources or Human sciences? Do you want to know how professionals landed their career or what they wished they did during college? Our monthly &amp;ldquo;Ask me Anything&amp;rdquo; speaker series continues with Ana Zepeda, a Geography PhD student at UC Davis studying impacts of compounded disasters on farmers, specifically women farmers in Latin America and the Caribbean</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influencing Modern Agriculture with Data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2022/10/01/2022-10-01-influencing-modern-agriculture-with-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2022/10/01/2022-10-01-influencing-modern-agriculture-with-data/</guid>
      <description>Influencing Modern Agriculture with Data Data is important for organizations as they utilize analytics to improve decision-making, study repeated customer activity, track buyer satisfaction and identify opportunities for new products and services to meet growing market needs, giving them routes to implement new systems. In modern agriculture business, the market is continuing to evolve, allowing farmers to embrace data-driven solutions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Job Hunt Post Graduation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2022/09/12/2022-09-12-job-hunt-post-graduation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2022/09/12/2022-09-12-job-hunt-post-graduation/</guid>
      <description>How to: Prepare for your job hunt post graduation The stress of finding a job after graduation is extremely daunting. Luckily, the years of connections and experiences during your college career can help to assist you in this process. It is important to stay connected to those you have worked with, they can help with job ideas, strategies and support while navigating this search.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fall Career Conversations starting in September</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2022/09/02/2022-09-02-fall-ama-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2022/09/02/2022-09-02-fall-ama-start/</guid>
      <description>Are you interested in careers that use data to make informed decisions in the Food, Agriculture, Natural Resources or Human sciences? Do you want to know how professionals landed their career or what they wished they did during college? Our monthly &amp;ldquo;Ask me Anything&amp;rdquo; speaker series kicks off this month with Mariby Cruz - A Chico State Alumni!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Root of Data Science</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2022/09/02/2022-09-26-the-root-of-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2022/09/02/2022-09-26-the-root-of-data-science/</guid>
      <description>The Root of Data Science Many people may think of data science as a more modern career path. While the history of Big Data is indeed short, the precursors paving the way for this mega enterprise date back thousands of years ago.&#xA;According to the World Economic Forum, the beginning of early data was marked by the use of tally sticks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Things You Can do Right Now to Launch Your Professional Career</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2022/08/29/2022-08-29-4-things-you-can-do-right-now-to-launch-your-professional-career/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2022/08/29/2022-08-29-4-things-you-can-do-right-now-to-launch-your-professional-career/</guid>
      <description>4 Things You Can do Right Now to Launch Your Professional Career “Use your resources.” We hear it all the time as students. But how can using your campus career opportunities actually have an impact on your future? Sometimes, students don’t know where to start when looking to enter the professional world after graduation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Women in Data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2022/08/01/2022-08-01-women-in-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2022/08/01/2022-08-01-women-in-data/</guid>
      <description>Women in Data Whether it is in school, the workplace or daily life in general, it is no secret that women are a group whose challenges grow and evolve daily. The obstacles they face are no different in the world of data, where women face major inclusion barriers.&#xA;A report issued by the 2020 National Center for Women and Information Technology (NCWIT), concluded that in the world of data literacy, women are 57% of the workforce, but hold only 26% of data and analytics jobs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grants and Scholarships</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2022/07/11/2022-07-11-grants-and-scholarships/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2022/07/11/2022-07-11-grants-and-scholarships/</guid>
      <description>Grants and Scholarships Help Students: Here’s Why When students first apply to college, one major factor that often plays into their decision is whether or not they can afford to attend the university. Luckily, with the help of scholarships and federal grants, many students are able to achieve their goals of attending college.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to: Networking as a College Student</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2022/06/15/2022-06-15-networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2022/06/15/2022-06-15-networking/</guid>
      <description>While in college, networking is extremely valuable when trying to navigate life post-graduation. Networking allows leaders and peers in specific fields to give students tips, advices and knowledge about the various paths they can take to become established and successful.&#xA;Networking begins communication with other professionals by putting a face to your name.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Value of Data Literacy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2022/05/25/2022-05-25-the-value-of-data-literacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2022/05/25/2022-05-25-the-value-of-data-literacy/</guid>
      <description>4 Reasons why understanding data is key In today&amp;rsquo;s digital age, data is everywhere. Being able to understand and analyze data is known as data literacy. In both educational and professional settings, data literacy skills are vital to success. Data is virtually in every space. We are constantly looking at numbers, text, images, videos, and our personal data is always being collected as we are actively using our phones or computers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Thrilling, Statistic-Filled Weekend at Chico State Data Fest 2022</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2022/05/04/2022-05-04-datafest-2022-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2022/05/04/2022-05-04-datafest-2022-recap/</guid>
      <description>Chico State Data Fest 2022 Recap On April 1-3rd, Chico State University hosted the ASA DataFest 2022. DataFest is an event hosted by the Chico State Data Initiative (DSI), organized by the Mathematics &amp;amp; Statistics department and Project DA-FANH&amp;rsquo;s project director Robin Donatello. Students were presented with undisclosed data on Friday and then worked through the weekend to gain the best insights into the confidential, real-world data sets.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>$25k Fellowship opportunity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2022/02/21/2022-02-21-25k-fellowship-opportunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2022/02/21/2022-02-21-25k-fellowship-opportunity/</guid>
      <description>USDA offers a $25K fellowship opportunity for a student through Project DA-FANH Through Project DA-FANH, the United States Department of Agriculture is offering a $25k fellowship to one undergraduate student. The fellowship program will cover an entire year of tuition, provide funded research support and conference travel opportunities. If you are a Chico State student who is interested in pursuing a career related to Data Science, Data Analytics or the Food, Agriculture, Natural Resources and Human Sciences (FANH) domain and who has faced or faces social, educational or economic barriers, you may be eligible to apply.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Carpentry for Enhancing Teaching and Research using R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2021/12/01/2021-12-01-workshop1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2021/12/01/2021-12-01-workshop1/</guid>
      <description>We are excited for the kickoff of our workshop series. Our first and upcoming workshop will be on January 13th - 14th, 2022 and hope you are too. A few notes:&#xA;Be sure to complete the pre-workshop survey. We use this to calibrate the pace of the workshop and, together with a post-workshop survey, to assess how it went.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project Launch</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6407/blog/2021/08/01/2021-08-01-project-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6407/blog/2021/08/01/2021-08-01-project-launch/</guid>
      <description>How two institutions partnered to enhance the quality of undergraduate education for Hispanic students CHICO, C.A. - CSU Chico and CSU San Bernardino are two Hispanic Serving Institutions in the California State University system. These universities are collaborating to enhance the quality of college education at the intersection of Data Science and Analytics (DS/DA) and the Food, Agriculture, Natural resources and Human sciences (FANH).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
